KAVITHA SREE ANNALDESH

+1 4373667665 | kavithasree999@gmail.com | Scarborough, ON M1J1J8

SUMMARY

Collaborative, detail-oriented Technical Writer with 6+ years of experience. Designing and developing new documents in conformance with technical specifications and standards. Proficiency in writing short, crisp, and precise information and instructions for the audience. First-rate communication and interpersonal skills with proven abilities in resolving complex issues.

SKILLS

Development Skills

- Microsoft Office
- Madcap flare
- Adobe RoboHelp
- Oxygen XML, DITA
- Adobe FrameMaker
- Camtasia
- Snagit
- Microsoft Visio
- JIRA & Confluence

- 1411010501011110

Writing Standards

- Microsoft manual of style for Publications (MSTP)
- Simplified Technical English (STE)
- Customer Style Guides

Process

- Agile
- Waterfall
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Document Development Life Cycle (DDLC)

Data Analysis and Visualization

- Microsoft Excel
- Power Bi

EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer | ONxpress Transportation Partners | Jan 2023 - Present Toronto, Canada

- Engaged in the design and formulation of templates, as well as the establishment of procedures and methodologies to enhance efficiency across diverse processes
- Designed and developed detailed process documentation to ensure precision and consistency, and established standardized procedures for efficient workflow.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to gather comprehensive insights into their specific process requirements.
- Performed comprehensive analysis to meet team requirements, gaining a profound understanding of process workflows. Translated team needs into precise and actionable documentation, including tool specifications.
- Instituted and upheld standardized documentation protocols to foster uniformity across multiple teams.
- Conducted interactive training sessions to equip team members with practical skills in utilizing new documentation and tools.
- Provided continuous assistance to ensure the successful execution of procedures.
- Implemented inventive measures to optimize process efficiency and productivity.
- Engaged in collaborative efforts with teams throughout the organization to gather a spectrum of perspectives for enhancing processes.
- Designed Excel-based working documents featuring necessary fields to streamline the process of data entry and analysis. Furthermore, established dashboards to systematically measure and track the progress of validated processes.

Technical Writer | FTD India Pvt Ltd | May 2022 - October 2022 Hyderabad, India

- Created user documentation for various aspects and developed user guides and instruction manuals.
- Collaborated with engineers, product managers, and instructional designers in the development of internal and external documentation.
- Created document templates as per process requirements which include styles, consistent wordings, and formatting.
- Worked on Epics (User story) in JIRA to update the release note in Confluence for internal references.
- Attended product team meetings to understand the ongoing process and proposed the developments proactively to update or initiate the required documentation process.
- Develop instructional videos demonstrating the process workflows to guide users in achieving their objectives.
- Participated in the teamwork to create and update the developer (API) documents.

Technical Writer | Zyoin Web Pvt Ltd | April 2021 - May 2022 Hyderabad, India

- As part of the Product Management team, I developed client-facing product content that describes the product and provides instructions on using product features.
- Assisted in the process of identification, creation, and project management of product content and its information management strategy for Product Management.
- Product knowledge development and expertise in multiple areas related to content as per business requirements.
- Implementation of project management methods for content creation and management tools.
- Provided deliverables and services, including product documentation and role-based feedback on product features, enabling client independence and optimal use of products.

Data Analyst | Camp Systems Pvt Ltd | June 2016 - January 2020 Hyderabad, India

My career started at Camp Systems in 2016 as a Graduate hire; in the years following, I worked on various reports to ensure quality and standards.

- Analyzed the data from the maintenance documents and developed precise technical manuals, user manuals, installation guides, and end-user document manuals for the clients and support team.
- Developed documents at different phases such as design requirements, assembly, test procedures, certification requirements, and service manuals.
- Key responsibilities include handling the documentation for creating and updating the operation and repair manuals.
- Created technical manual, user manual, installation guide, end-user document, productive information manuals, and release notes as per client requirements.

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Technology, Aeronautical Engineering, JNTU April 2016.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Technical Writer, Aerotech ILS, Hyderabad.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Recognized as Employee of the year for Outstanding Quality Contributor.